<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CONSELF Docs</title>
    <link>https://apalazzin.github.io/conself-docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content on CONSELF Docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://apalazzin.github.io/conself-docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>3D Fuser</title>
      <link>https://apalazzin.github.io/conself-docs/validation/3d-fuser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apalazzin.github.io/conself-docs/validation/3d-fuser/</guid>
      <description>[To be completed …]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CAD Files</title>
      <link>https://apalazzin.github.io/conself-docs/hints/cad-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apalazzin.github.io/conself-docs/hints/cad-files/</guid>
      <description>The generation of a CAD file is one of the most important parts of any CFD simulation. CONSELF can handle multiple geometry types in order to help the user during his task. At the same time, it is recommendable to follow some basics tricks in order to be confident about the final result of the simulation and avoid geometry errors and mesh inconsistencies.
Create fluid volumes In order to run a CFD simulation you have to generate the volume of fluid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credits management and statistics</title>
      <link>https://apalazzin.github.io/conself-docs/manual/credits-management-and-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apalazzin.github.io/conself-docs/manual/credits-management-and-statistics/</guid>
      <description>CONSELF it is a pay-per-use CFD application available via browser. In order to enjoy this service, you must activate one of the available plans. When entering the application you can access two main pages: the dashboard and the simulations. Before proceeding to the part concerning the CFD, let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at what is reported in the dashboard. In here you keep under control the whole application and you have at a glance all the information about your simulations and credits availability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>External Link</title>
      <link>https://apalazzin.github.io/conself-docs/contributing/external-link/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apalazzin.github.io/conself-docs/contributing/external-link/</guid>
      <description>Software CAD and 3D modelling Onshape - Fully cloud solution for 3D modelling
Blender - 3D modelling software popular in FabLabs and 3D printing
DraftSight - Free 2D CAD software by Dassauld Systemes
FreeCAD - 3D modelling in an opensource environment
SketchUp - Another free 3D modelling software
File formats  STEP files (reference here) Initial Graphics Exchange Specification - IGES files (reference here) STereoLithography - STL standard files, both ASCII and BINARY (reference here)  CFD info and communities CFD Online - An online center for Computational Fluid Dynamics with services like discussion forums, jobs, links and a wiki</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boundary Conditions</title>
      <link>https://apalazzin.github.io/conself-docs/hints/boundaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apalazzin.github.io/conself-docs/hints/boundaries/</guid>
      <description>The table below report an overview of available boundary conditions and specifications. The description specifies the application and the restriction of the boundary conditions.
Boundary availability depends on the application you are currently using.
    Boundary Description    INLET - Absolute velocity   Inlet velocity - Velocity vector is specified in an absolute reference frame   Uabsx [m/s] - Absolute velocity X Uabsy [m/s] - Absolute velocity Y Uabsz [m/s] - Absolute velocity Z Dₕ [m] - Hydraulic diameter      INLET - Cylindrical velocity   Inlet velocity in a cylindrical reference frame   Centre X [m] - Centre X Centre Y [m] - Centre Y Centre Z [m] - Centre Z Axis X - Normalized axis X Axis Y - Normalized axis Y Axis Z - Normalized axis Z U axial [m/s] - Axial velocity U radial [m/s] - Radial velocity ω [rpm] - Rotational velocity Dₕ [m] - Hydraulic diameter      INLET - Relative velocity   Inlet velocity - Velocity vector is specified in a relative reference frame   Urelx [m/s] - Relative velocity X Urely [m/s] - Relative velocity Y Urelz [m/s] - Relative velocity Z Dₕ [m] - Hydraulic diameter      INLET - Total pressure   Total pressure inlet condition - valid also for outlet condition   p₀ [Pa] - Total Pressure Dₕ [m] - Hydraulic diameter      INLET - Velocity   Inlet velocity - Velocity vector normal to the surface (use negative value for outflow)   U [m/s] - Velocity Dₕ [m] - Hydraulic diameter Φ [%] - Fluid-A concentration      INLET - Velocity and particles   Inlet velocity with specified inlet particles   U [m/s] - Fluid velocity Uxp [m/s] - Particles velocity X Uyp [m/s] - Particles velocity Y Uzp [m/s] - Particles velocity Z Mp [kg/s] - Particles mass flow Dp [m] - Particles dimension Dₕ [m] - Hydraulic diameter      INLET - Velocity fixed temperature   Inlet velocity with specified temperature - Velocity vector normal to the surface   U [m/s] - Velocity T [K] - Temperature Dₕ [m] - Hydraulic diameter      INLET - Velocity vector   Inlet velocity where the user specifies the velocity vector   Ux [m/s] - Velocity X Uy [m/s] - Velocity Y Uz [m/s] - Velocity Z Dₕ [m] - Hydraulic diameter Φ [%] - Fluid-A concentration      INLET - Velocity vector fixed temperature   Inlet velocity where the user specifies the velocity vector and the temperature   Ux [m/s] - Velocity X Uy [m/s] - Velocity Y Uz [m/s] - Velocity Z T [K] - Temperature Dₕ [m] - Hydraulic diameter      INLET - Volume flow   Inlet condition with prescribed volume flow (use negative value for outflow)   Q [m³/s] - Volume flow Dₕ [m] - Hydraulic diameter      OUTLET - Pressure   Outlet condition for pressure - Backscatter flow is denied   p [Pa] - Pressure      WALL - Adiabatic no slip   No slip adiabatic wall   Ux [m/s] - Velocity X Uy [m/s] - Velocity Y Uz [m/s] - Velocity Z      WALL - Fire fixed temperature   No slip wall with prescribed temperature   Ux [m/s] - Velocity X Uy [m/s] - Velocity Y Uz [m/s] - Velocity Z CO [kg/(s·m²)] - CO production T [K] - Temperature      WALL - Fire heat flux   No slip wall with imposed temperature gradient   Ux [m/s] - Velocity X Uy [m/s] - Velocity Y Uz [m/s] - Velocity Z CO [kg/(s·m²)] - CO production T [K/m] - Temperature gradient      WALL - Fire location   No slip wall with imposed temperature gradient   Ux [m/s] - Velocity X Uy [m/s] - Velocity Y Uz [m/s] - Velocity Z CO [kg/(s·m²)] - CO production q [W/m²] - Heat flux      WALL - No slip   No slip adiabatic wall   Ux [m/s] - Velocity X Uy [m/s] - Velocity Y Uz [m/s] - Velocity Z      WALL - No slip fixed temperature   No slip wall with imposed temperature   Ux [m/s] - Velocity X Uy [m/s] - Velocity Y Uz [m/s] - Velocity Z T [K] - Temperature      WALL - No slip rough wall   No slip rough wall   Ux [m/s] - Velocity X Uy [m/s] - Velocity Y Uz [m/s] - Velocity Z Ks [m] - Sand-grain roughness height Cs - Roughness constant      WALL - No slip with CO production   No slip wall with imposed CO production   Ux [m/s] - Velocity X Uy [m/s] - Velocity Y Uz [m/s] - Velocity Z CO [kg/(s·m²)] - CO production      WALL - No slip with heat flux   No slip wall with imposed heat flux per surface unit   Ux [m/s] - Velocity X Uy [m/s] - Velocity Y Uz [m/s] - Velocity Z q [W/m²] - Heat flux      WALL - No slip with heat power   No slip wall with imposed global heat flux   Ux [m/s] - Velocity X Uy [m/s] - Velocity Y Uz [m/s] - Velocity Z Q [W] - Heat power      WALL - Rotating   Rotating adiabatic wall   Centre X [m] - Centre X Centre Y [m] - Centre Y Centre Z [m] - Centre Z Axis X - Normalized axis X Axis Y - Normalized axis Y Axis Z - Normalized axis Z ω [rpm] - Rotational velocity      WALL - Rotating no slip   Rotating adiabatic wall   ω [rpm] - Relative rotational speed      WALL - Rotating no slip rough wall   No slip rotating rough wall   ω [rpm] - Relative rotational speed Ks [m] - Sand-grain roughness height Cs - Roughness constant      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CONSELF simulation process</title>
      <link>https://apalazzin.github.io/conself-docs/manual/conself-simulation-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apalazzin.github.io/conself-docs/manual/conself-simulation-process/</guid>
      <description>Using CONSELF means entering a new mindset, a new philosophy of simulating. Therefore, in order to be able to read and understand the following tutorials, bear in mind the following key definitions:
Simulation: a mathematical procedure that allows to reproduce in a virtual environment - software - a physical behavior. Compared to laboratory tests, it is a quicker and cheaper process. Ultimately, simulations help engineers validate the hypothesis behind every design phase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lid Driven Cavity</title>
      <link>https://apalazzin.github.io/conself-docs/validation/lid-driven-cavity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apalazzin.github.io/conself-docs/validation/lid-driven-cavity/</guid>
      <description>GEOMETRY Input file from File:LidDriven.stp
File data  In File units select Millimeters In Grouping Criteria STEP select By Curve Entity  Domain  In Flow Type select Internal  MESH2D Surface mesh Complete this section by filling the input data according to the following table
   Boundary name Uniformity level [%] Max element size [m]     BC-Parte1FACE1 70 0.04   BC-Parte1FACE2 70 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GEOMETRY</title>
      <link>https://apalazzin.github.io/conself-docs/manual/geometry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apalazzin.github.io/conself-docs/manual/geometry/</guid>
      <description>The geometry step represents the phase in which the user defines the main geometrical characteristics of the case. The user is required to draw a complete geometry using a CAD software - see External Link to find free CAD softwares available on the internet that can be used with CONSELF CFD on Cloud. In order to get more information about the generation of CAD files, see this page.
CONSELF can handle multiple unit systems and, furthermore, the user interface has the capability to generate a wind-tunnel geometry around the geometry, in order to speed up the setup process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Errors</title>
      <link>https://apalazzin.github.io/conself-docs/hints/errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apalazzin.github.io/conself-docs/hints/errors/</guid>
      <description>After each STEPS has been performed, it is possible to check its results by clicking on the steps summary button. This will report a summary table where RED items are problematic steps. For each problem an error message, with a brief description and suggested action is reported. For the sake of clarity, we report a more detailed description of the problem and the suggested solution to make even easier to our customers the web-application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wind Turbine</title>
      <link>https://apalazzin.github.io/conself-docs/validation/wind-turbine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apalazzin.github.io/conself-docs/validation/wind-turbine/</guid>
      <description>Check this validation of OpenFOAM® against Fluent.
   Courtesy of grantjfan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MESH</title>
      <link>https://apalazzin.github.io/conself-docs/manual/mesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apalazzin.github.io/conself-docs/manual/mesh/</guid>
      <description>Mesh is the STEP required in order to define the mesh.
Volume mesh In this section the user is asked to define the mesh algorithm and the basic mesh feature.
 Meshing algorithm: drop down list from which the user has to select the meshing algorithm (see pictures below).
 Hexahedral: by using this algorithm, a fully cartesian grid is obtained. Depending on the mesh dimension specifications on the boundaries, local grid refinements are applied to meet the resolution constraints.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFD</title>
      <link>https://apalazzin.github.io/conself-docs/manual/cfd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apalazzin.github.io/conself-docs/manual/cfd/</guid>
      <description>The CFD step represents the widest part of the whole simulation settings. The parameters present in the current step may vary according to the application chosen.
Fluid Models The first section is about defining the fluid models, turbulence and density in particular.
 Flow type: drop down list from which the user has to select the flow type
 Incompressible: to simulate incompressible fluids like water, oil or air at low velocity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RESULTS</title>
      <link>https://apalazzin.github.io/conself-docs/manual/results/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apalazzin.github.io/conself-docs/manual/results/</guid>
      <description>CONSELF offers a web based application to postprocess results. Have a look at the following video to check out the most important features of this web application.
   Beside this tool, there are two more functionalities, highlighted in the picture: residual plot and results download. The first one displays the residuals of pressure and velocity fields obtained during the calculation, the latter instead allows to download the results in your local machine.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>